# Joseph Manto

joemanto.dev+jobs@gmail.com

https://manto.dev | https://github.com/JoeManto | https://linkedin.com/in/joemanto

iOS and macOS developer with 10 years of freelance experience and 2+ years of professional experience developing apps, frameworks, and tools. Acquiring a vast knowledge base of the Apple development ecosystem along the way.

## **Professional Experience**

## VMware iOS Developer | Member of Technical Staff 2

- Provided code and design contributions for customer-facing NIAP-compliant (security standard) apps.
- Led the design and development of in-app analytics efforts in two core apps. Allowing app stakeholders to make informed data-driven decisions.
- Implemented a Zoom OAuth client allowing zoom integration for users
- Collaborated in and with internal and external agile teams all around the world
- Designed and contributed to an iOS widgets integration

### Remote June 2020 - Present

- Experience working on apps that utilize a central SDK
- Experience working with apps that use Swift and Obj-C as well as UIKit and SwiftUI
- Worked on apps that have native versions on other platforms (iOS & macOS & Android)
- Worked on multiple distributed code bases
- Experience creating and working with CocoaPods and Swift Package Manag

#### Dec 2016 - May 2020

 Worked in a team environment leading and helping staff solve problems.

Western Michigan University Student Lead & Web Dev

- Developed management skills with a focus on problem-solving.
- Collaboration on problems with co-workers.

- Developed and shipped a service on the university network that allowed employees to trade shifts with each other
- The ability to visualize problems from the customer's point of view.

# iOS Skills

 $\textbf{Actively Using:} \ Swift, Swift UI, MVVM, Dependency Injection, Concurrency (Swift \& GCD), CoreData, KeyChain, Concurrency (Swift & GCD), CoreData, CoreData, CoreData, CoreData, CoreData, CoreData, CoreData, CoreData, Co$ 

UserDefaults, UIKit, XCT

Previously Used: Combine, WidgetKit, StoreKit, SpriteKit, SnapshotTesting, Accessibility Inspector, SQlite, Obj-C

Other Skills: Git, Docker, Xcode, Jira, BitBucket, Bamboo

# **Projects** (More hosted on Github)

Haptic Feedback Keyboard - iOS App
 Haptic Feedback is an app that provides a keyboard extension that offers haptic feedback per keyboard press prior to iOS 13

## XCT - CLI Tool - C

Preprocessor and wrapper on Apple's XcodeBuild test runner. Making running tests using the command line powerful, flexible, and quick

• Super View - macOS App

SuperView is a macOS app that allows users to create `always on top` windows that can be used to view files and web pages

# Education Western Michigan University

Aug 2016 - May 2020